毛毛原创字幕，不太完善，转载请注明出处
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
把他带这来
Bring him here.
在我们祖先那时候
In the time of our ancestors
我们族人的循环再世位置就在孩子的手中
the cycle of our people lay in the hands of the children.
在部落中孩子是造物主留下的
A child's position in the tribe was left to the maker.
孩子的方位标志显现要早于大人
Children bearing marks were brought before the elders
这儿，它们是被赐予的标记
there, they were given titles...
这些标记将跟随他一生
...titles that would last a lifetime.
智慧
Wisdom...
勇气
Courage...
想象力
Vision.
这个孩子有着我们祖先
This boy holds the holy marks
神圣的标记
of our ancestors.
他会是个领导者
He is a leader.
他会是个先知
He is a prophet.
我们应该听从他
We should listen to him.
一个国家的诞生
我看见你了
I see you!
纳特
Nat?
Nat!
好吧，你又赢了
All right, you win again.
出来
Come on out!
萨姆？过来吃晚饭了
Sam? You come on in here for supper!
好的
Yessum.
再见，纳特
Bye, nat.
再见
Bye.
你就像蝙蝠的眼睛
You so much as bat an eye,
我要把你从这打回地狱去
I'm gonna blow you from here to hell.
你在外面做什么，伙计？
What you doin' out here, boy?
从我的主人那装点食物
Pickin' up some food for my master,
本杰明 特纳
Benjamin Turner.
在午夜时间？转过来
In the middle of the night? Turn around.
你的通行许可在哪？
here your pass at?
拿过来，快点
Bring it on. C'mon! Bring it!
退回去
Get back.
你觉得你比我聪明，是不是？
You think you're smarter than me, don't you, boy?
没有，先生
No, sir.
杰西，我们怎么叫黑鬼的
Jesse, who do we call a nigger
谁会觉得他比一个白人更精明？
who done think he can outsmart a white man?
死了的黑鬼
A dead nigger.
转过来
Turn around.
跪下
On your knees.
这是你自己找的
You done this to yourself, boy.
- 发生什么了？ － 上床去
- What happened?  - Go on to bed.
我偷食物被抓了
I got caught stealing food.
我杀了看守，我得逃走了
I killed a slave catcher. I gotta go.
你照顾好你母亲和娜娜，知道吗？
You take care of your mom and Nana, you hear?
你是神的孩子
You a child of god.
你意志坚定
You got purpose. It's in you.
上帝把它放在了这
The lord put it there,
没有任何人和事可以把它们夺走
and there ain't nothing nobody can do to take it away.
你明白了？
You hear?
是的
Yes, sir.
现在你上床去
Now you go ahead on and go to bed.
我可能快点回来
I'll be back for y'all as soon as I can.
回床上去，我们睡觉
Go on back to bed. Go on to bed, girl! We sleep!
布里奇特，南希，起来了
Bridget! Nancy! Y'all wake up!
艾萨克有大麻烦了
Isaac's in a lot of trouble.
我需要你们当中的人告诉我他去哪里了
I need one of y'all to tell me where he is.
不知道去哪了，主人，我们一晚没见他
Don't know where he is, massa. We ain't seen him all night.
你确定
You sure?
本，我命令你离开
Ben, I'm gonna ask you to leave.
- 嗯？ - 今晚一个白人丧命了
- Huh?  - A white man has lost his life tonight.
你知道这样说代表着接下去要发生什么样的事，走
You know like I do what that mean. Get!
现在，我要给他们些颜色看看
Now, any harm done to these people,
我要报告警长，我是认真的
I'm gonna call the sheriff! I'm serious!
你们没人知道他在那？
None of y'all know where he is, huh?
没有，先生
No, sir.
他妈的
Goddamnit.
你知道吗，孩子？
What about you, boy?
他也什么不知道
He don't know nothing, either.
你父亲在那？
Where's your daddy at?
听着，你不告诉我他在那
Now listen, you don't tell me where he's at,
其它人也会找到他
someone else is gonna find him,
他们会杀了他
and they gonna kill him.
你告诉我，我会安全把他带回来
You tell me, I'll go get him.I'll bring him back here safe.
好吗？
All right?
告诉我你父亲在哪
Tell me where daddy's at.
说话，不要一言不发
Say it. Spit something outta that mouth! Say it!
告诉我在哪
Tell me where he's at!
他妈的
Goddamnit.
你是那个黑鬼的孩子，好吧
You that nigger's boy, all right.
如果让我发现你在说谎
If I find out y'all's been lying,
我会再回来的，到时我就不客气了
I'm gonna come back here, i ain't gonna be so nice...
主人，不要，不要，上帝啊！
Oh, massa, please! Please! Massa, please! Oh, lord!
够了，住手
All right, that's... That's enough! Stop!
你最好教教那个孩子礼貌
You best teach that boy some manners.
下次，他要用眼睛看着我
Next time he look me in the eye,
你父亲也会是这个结果
you gonna get the same thing what waitin' for his pa.
可以帮你吗？
Mind if I help you?
不用了
No, ma'am.
萨缪尔告诉我早上的事情了
Samuel told me something this morning
我想要向你打听下
I wanted to ask you about.
他说纳特知道怎么读
He said, nat knows how to read.
纳特不知道怎么读
Nat don't not know how to read.
做为我自己是不相信的
Part of me couldn't believe it myself.
所以我测试了他
So I tested him.
十分肯定
Sure enough,
他就在哪大声朗读
there he was sounding out letters.
你明天午饭后把他带来
You have him come by the house tomorrow after lunch.
他没有恶意
He don't mean no harm.
下次我看见他我会抽他一顿
I'ma whip him good the next time I see him.
抽他？不要
Whip him? Nonsense.
我要教育他
I'm gonna teach him.
如果万能的主给了这个孩子阅读的能力
If the good lord gave that boy a gift to read,
我们就不应该怠慢它，浪费它
we'd be remiss to let it go to waste.
你不要希望他能任何时候都能回家
And don't expect him back anytime soon.
他会和我们在主屋一起生活一段时间
He'll be living with us in the main house for a while.
课程最好在开始时就不要被打断
Lessons best not be disturbed in the beginning.
好的，夫人
Yes, ma'am.
没关系，孩子，不是真的
It's okay, baby. It's okay. It ain't real.
不是真的，没事了，它在你的心里
It ain't real. It's all right. It's in your mind.
它在你的心里
It's in your mind.
妈妈在这
Momma's here now.
我要父亲
Want my poppa.
我也是的，孩子
Me too, baby.
我也是
Me too.
把你的手臂穿过去
Put your arms through.
多帅气
How handsome.
他会没事的
He'll be all right.
这些书是给白人看的
These books are for white folks.
这里有着你无法理解的全部事情
They're full of things your kind wouldn't understand.
但是我会让你读一本特别的书
But I do have a special one just for you.
你猜是什么？
And guess what?
是有史以来最好的一本书
It's the best book ever written.
你是个特别的孩子
You're a special boy, Nathaniel.
努力学习听从我的指令，知道吗？
Study hard and heed my instructions, hear?
你的人生
Your life,
将会与众不同
it'll never be the same.
我能预见到
I'll see to that.
是，太太
Yes, missus.
创世纪，开始
"Genesis. In the beginning..."
开始
In the beginning...
这儿，这个词是这儿
Here, this word here, "the."
那是狡猾，机警
That's tricky. Now, these letters "t-h."
无论何时你看见他们
Whenever you see them...
洁净你的双手，罪人们
"...cleanse your hands, ye sinners...
心怀二意的人们，净化你们的心灵
"And purify your hearts, ye double-minded.
被折磨，悲哀，哭泣
"Be afflicted, and mourn, and weep.
让你的笑声变成了悲哀
"Let your laughter be turned to mourning,
和你的快乐变成忧伤
"and your joy to heaviness."
雅各书，第四章，第八至九篇
James 4, chapter 8 and 9.
随我翻到雅各书第一章
Turn with me, if you would, to James 1.
握着耶和华的恩惠
Holding on to the goodness of the lord.
在他去陪伴上帝之前，我曾对本说
I spoke to Ben, before he went on to be with the lord.
他觉得你作为一个农场工人会对我们家庭更有用
He felt you'd be more useful to our family as a field hand.
我很抱歉，纳特
I'm sorry, nat.
现在，你要从这开始
Now, you gonna start here,
你要去远一点的地方开始工作
and you're gonna work your way down yonder.
而我会在这里，明白吗？
And I'll be right over here. You hear?
嗯
Ah!
谢谢你，兄弟
Thank you, brother.
我已经不省人事了，除非我有看见
I had fainted, unless I had believed to see,
上帝的善良
the goodness of the lord
在我们生活的土地上
in the land of the living.
等待上帝的到来
Wait on the lord,
要变的善良勇敢
be of good courage,
他会使你的内心强大
and he shall strengthen thine heart.
等会，我说
Wait, I say,
依靠上帝
on the lord.
让我们低下我们的头颅
Let us bow our heads.
萨姆，那是你姐姐？
Sam, that sister of yours,
真是能成为个好老婆
gonna make a fine wife indeed.
我说的是真的
It's been a true blessing
看着她变成一个女人
seeing her develop into the woman that she is.
这可是个美好的祝福
It'd be an even better blessing
看她和她的母亲
seein' her and momma
她们把脚放在他桌子下而不是我的
put their feet under his table instead of mine.
我得说
I gotta say,
萨姆，你的奴隶确信知道怎么守规矩
Sam, your slaves sure do know how to behave.
每次我来都令我印象深刻
I'm impressed with them every time I come around.
好的，他们当中有个牧师
Well, they god fearin'. One of them's a preacher.
没人告诉我
No one's gotta tell you
干旱的日子真是太难熬了
the times are tough with the drought.
在这个国家对白人来说变得更艰难了
It's gettin' harder for the whites in this county
要给他们的黑人奴隶吃好穿好
to clothe and feed their niggers good.
这些关于暴动的谈论
Talks of insurrection
让白人家伙感到害怕
got folks scared.
我觉得人们应该付出更好的工资报酬
I think people might pay good money
可以让这些人能更冷静些
to have them calm down a bit.
特别是一个他们自己人
Especially by one of their own.
噢
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
你看见一个黑鬼从这跑过吗？
You seen a nigger run past here?
我睡着了没看见
Naw. Then again i doze off for a few.
你看见了吗，孩子？
What about you, boy?
最好现在不要撒谎，你骗不过我的
Best not lie now. I know when y'all's lyin'.
没有，先生
No, sir.
两个比尔琼斯地方的
Couple of niggers went missin'
黑鬼不见了今天早上
off bill Johnson's place this mornin'.
说是在逃跑之前
Say they raised up on an overseer
他们举起了工头
before they took off.
好的，看见什么就告诉我
All right, you see somethin' let us know.
好的
Will do.
驾
Giddyup.
你把这里结束了，我去广场里面
You finish up here, I'll go square up inside.
好的，先生
Yes, sir.
夫人，杨斯掉了这个
Ma'am. The youngin', he dropped this a step back.
谢谢
Thank ya.
你在干什么那？
Whatcha think you're doin'?
他只是…你和我妻子说话了
He was just tryin'... You spoke to my wife.
你主人在那？
Where's your owner, boy?
问你话那
I asked you a question.
你最好收起你的棍子来
You best goin' to put that stick down now!
我要找警长了
I want the sheriff.
这个家伙羞辱了我
his boy assaulted me!
他羞辱了我妻子
He assaulted my wife!
我要指控他
And I'm bringin' charges!
弗洛伊德警长？
Sheriff Floyd?
好的，他归你了，如果你喜欢
All right, you fetch him if you like.
但同时我数三下
But in the meantime i will give you
你把棍子放下来
to the count of three to put your stick down
在我给你一些真实的指控之前
before I give you some real charges
让他回到这里
to give him when he gets here.
你威胁我
You threatnin' me?
一
One.
二
Two.
走吧，带着孩子
C'mon, get the boy.
回家
Let's get home.
我们的玉米很甜
We got sweet corn!
来吧，来点玉米粉
C'mon now! Get your grits!
我们这玉米很甜
We got sweet corn here.
看一看
Here you go.
在这的这个
And this one here!
强壮如牛
Strong as an ox!
虽然不起眼，但是年轻的体内流动着活力的种子
Nothin' but good seed flowin' from this here buck.
看看他们的牙齿
Look at them teeth. Huh?
我将开始拍卖
I'll start him out at...
两百
200.
一百五
150?
拜托了，我还得在这接着混那
C'mon now, I gotta make a living here, gents.
一百？七十五？
100? 75?
成交，带走吧
Sold! Get outta here.
给他套上束具，带那个女过来
Put a yoke on him. Bring her up here.
现在，大家可以考虑下这个标致的乡下妞
Now, consider this comely wench.
不超过十八岁
Not a day over 18.
好吧，我从一百七十五元开始起拍
All right, I'll start her off at 175.
我出一百七十五元，还有出价的吗？
I got 175. Do I hear two?
现在出价两百二十五了
Now we're talkin'! Do I got 225?
主人，那个乡下女孩可以当作礼物送给
Massa, that wench there sure would make
凯瑟琳小姐
a good weddin' gift for miss Catherine.
两百二十五
225!
你一直在说小姐在问你
You keep sayin' she been askin'.
你出两百五吗？
Do I hear 250?
她看着十分年轻，如果你问我的话
She looks right young, if you ask me.
快点！
C'mon now.
对的，先生，她很年轻，给我两百五
You right, sir, she young. Gimme 250.
但是如果跟对人的话
C'mon. But with the right teacher,
- 一个像这样的姑娘？ - 两百五
- a wench like that?  - 250.
可以工作很长一段时间了
Could be workin' a long time.
两百七十五元
There it is! 275?
主人，我们应该
Massa, sure would be a shame to watch her
用一个低价买了她
go to waste for such a low price.
你知道个屁
And what the hell would you know about
什么是高什么是低？
what's a little and what's a lot, huh?
我不知道你最近怎么了
I don't know what's gotten into you lately,
但不论是什么，你最好放弃
but whatever it is, you better quit.
你看见我看到的了吗？
Are you seein' what I'm seein'?
你带着个回家
You take this one home, you know,
把她洗干净了
clean her up,
不要太久
won't be long before you find yourself
你会比玩球的小狗还要高兴的
happier than a dog with three balls!
笑一笑，贱货
Smile, bitch.
两百五一次
That's 250 goin' once.
两百五两次
250 goin' twice.
- 两百七十五  - 两百七十五
- 275  - 275.
我们出两百七十五
We got 275!
两百七十五一次
275 goin' once.
两百七十五两次
275 goin' twice.
卖给后排那个善良的绅士了
Sold to that fine gentleman in the back!
喔
Whoa.
她没事的，先生
She be fine, sir.
我希望你是对的
I sure hope you're right.
你妈给她洗过吃了
Have your momma get her cleaned and fed.
- 先从擦地板开始  - 明白，先生
- Start breakin' her in.  - Yes, sir.
你和汉克可以从北面围栏那开始
You and hark can start on the north fence
- 这是明早的第一件事  - 明白，先生
- first thing in the morning.  - Yes, sir.
我不会伤害你的
I ain't gonna hurt you.
只是爬上来帮你出来
Just gonna climb up and help you out.
没事的
It's all right.
这孩子是谁？发生了什么？
Who is this child? What happened?
活力四射
Burnin' up.
是我的，这是我的裙子
This mine! This my dress! My dress! This my dress!
走开，出去
Go now! Get out, ya!
我们不会伤害你
We're not gonna hurt you. We're not gonna hurt you.
不要带走
Don't take it away.
笑一下
You just smile
让他们可以谈话，好吗？
and let them do the talkin'. All right?
好的
Yessum.
中午好，主人，这是切瑞安妮
Afternoon, massa. This here cherry-Ann.
主人
Massa.
凯瑟琳娜
Catherine!
凯瑟琳娜，这是切瑞安妮
Catherine, this here is cherry-Ann.
夫人
Missus.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you!
来吧，见下我母亲
Come on, i want you to meet momma.
母亲
Momma.
谢谢你
Thank you.
为了什么
For what?
你让她边得更好更漂亮了
For gettin' her better. For makin' her so beautiful.
我什么也没做
I didn't do nothin'.
那些美貌
That girl was brought into this world
都是那女孩与生俱来的
as beautiful as she could be.
很难过看到你和太太要走了
It sure is sad to see you and the missus go.
我们只是隔了一条路
We'll be just down the road.
当我们都安顿好了
When we get all good and settled,
我们会回来看看的
we'll come back and visit.
周日去教堂之后
On Sundays for church and that.
好吧，不急的
Well, there's no rush.
我开玩笑的，来这
Oh. I'm foolin'. Come here.
如果你有需要
If y'all need anything,
或者他对你不好，让我知道
or he ain't treatin' you right, you let me know.
是的，哥哥，我爱你
Yes, big brother. I love you.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
母亲，你准备好了吗？
Momma, you ready?
我很担心你，萨姆
I'm worried about you, Sam.
你要独自面对这么大的一个地方
This a big place to be out here all by yourself.
我没事的
I'll be fine.
你要小心
You take care now.
好的
All right. Hmm.
主人，为马准备的
Massa. For the horses.
就一个
Just one.
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
嗨
Hi.
我是纳特
I'm nat.
我知道
I know.
不好意思
Sorry for
打扰你了
fightin' you.
没事
Oh, that's fine.
嗯…
Um...
它们很漂亮
They're pretty.
在这四周发现的
Found them 'round here.
谢谢
Thank you.
再见
Bye.
就像我们在
Just as the planted crop
收割庄稼一样
is harvested in its own time,
主也在播种着我们
so too has the lord planted us.
赞美主啊
Good lord.
The good lord, the good lord
当我们完成了主赐予我们的工作时
will finish his work in us.
最后，我会敦促你们用心来敬奉上帝
So, in closing, i urge you all to take heart,
要用尽你们的一生
for god is at work in your life,
直到它的工作完成才算结束，阿门？
and he will not stop until his job is done. Amen?
阿门，解散
Amen. Dismissed!
仿佛命运已经注定永远
It seems like it's been forever
自从我上次看见你起
since I last seen you.
我们之间虽只有短短的几步
There were a few miles between us.
但我却感觉到很遥远
Just feels like so many more.
在哪过的还好吗？
How is it there?
很好，不像我以前待的地方
It's fine. Not like what I come from 'fore here.
多数时间我都是在照顾伊丽莎白小姐
Most days I'm just tending to miss Elizabeth
要不就是给凯瑟琳娜小姐拿这拿那的
or fetching this-that for miss Catherine.
如果你下周从教堂还回来的话？
You know if y'all coming back next week for church?
我很了解你
I know as much as you.
我猜想如果太太一直暗示下去
I suppose if missus is suggesting it,
里斯大人也不在意什么的
master Reese don't mind the trip.
我可不想等的太久才能见到你
I sure wouldn't wanna wait another season to see ya.
我也是的
Me, neither.
这是我奶奶从我爷爷那拿来的
My Nana got it from my grandaddy.
她被从非洲抓来时就一直带着它
She brought it with her when she was taken from Africa.
这是唯一能让她的心灵感到自由的东西
Said it was the only thing that kept her mind free.
很漂亮
It's pretty.
我把它送给你了
I want you to have it.
防止我有段时间不能见到你
In case I don't see you for a while, you
这个可以体醒你要时刻记住我
have something that reminds you of me.
我不知道是不是该收下
I don't know if it's right I take it.
我可没有能让你
'Sides, I don't have nothing to give you
思念我的东西给你
to remind you of me.
我已经对你念念不忘了
I spend all my time thinkin' about you already.
切瑞？
Cherry?
来帮下妈妈，可以走了
Come help with momma. It's time to go.
谁在那？
Who there?
纳特？
Nat?
你要干嘛？
What are you doin'?
我应该早点这样做
I shoulda done that earlier.
你就是专程来亲我的？
You came here to kiss me?
不是
No, no, no.
我要的比这多
I ain't got much.
我的信仰，妈妈，奶奶
My faith, momma, Nana.
直到现在，我要的更多
Up until now, enough.
切瑞，我希望你可以成我的妻子，我会无比的荣幸
Cherry, I'd feel right honored if you'd be my wife.
我会对你好的，用我的一生来保护你
I'd treat ya right. Protect ya with my life.
如果你嫁给我
If you'd have me.
我愿意
Yes. Yes, I will.
接下去怎么做？
What now?
嗯
Uh...
我会和萨缪尔先生谈谈
I talk it over with Samuel.
给我们找个小屋子，等你下次来的时候就会布置一新了
Get us a cabin set up when y'all visit.
好的
All right.
天父，我们今天齐聚一堂
Heavenly father.  We are gathered here today
来参加这两个孩子的婚礼
to join together these two children,
他们找到了爱的真谛
who have found the love that exists in you.
我们一直沐浴在爱的怀抱中
The love that surrounds all of us all the time.
我们祝福他们
We bless these children together with our hands
我们手捧鲜花与爱
that the love that flows through our hands...
哈喽，教士
Well, hello, reverend.
我没指望能在
I wasn't expecting to see you around
周日见到你
these parts 'till Sunday.
什么风把你吹来的？
What brings you around the middle of the week?
永远不要在错误的时间
Never a wrong time...
给一个基督兄弟带来祝福
...to bring a blessing to a brother in Christ.
噢，上帝
Oh lord.
这祝福要花钱吗？
Is this blessing gonna cost me money?
一个子也不要，实际从另一面来说
Not a penny. To the contrary, in fact.
艾塞亚，送点水来
Isaiah, run us out a water.
最好给我来些杜松子酒
Gin, if you please.
我要谈下关于你牧师的情况
So, I put the word out about your preacher.
有几个农民愿意出好价钱
Got a couple of farmers willing to turn a good coin.
- 是吗？ - 嗯
- Is that right?   - Mmm-hmm.
这些天价格看涨
Every bit counts these days.
哦
Oh.
啊
Ah!
嗯…
Mmm.
如果他能满足他们的愿望
If your boy does to their liking,
你能大赚一笔
you could get outta debt.
拯救你的农场
Save your farm.
所有这些都只要纳特牧师出面就行了
And all I gotta do is let nat preach.
就这么简单
That's it.
我不能担保这些家伙
Now, I'm not vouching for the character of these fellas.
是怎么运营这些生意的
What business they runnin' or how.
我就是来告诉你
I'm just here to tell you
有个机会可以尝试下
that there's an opportunity there.
你要做的就是好好利用它
One you got the means to capitalize on.
我们说的是哪里？
Whereabouts we talkin'?
是先从南安普敦开始的
In southampton, at the start.
好的，听起来不错
Well, sounds good enough.
细节我会在告诉你的
I'll send you the details.
姓名，地点，细节，我明天告诉你
Names, locations, and dates, I'd say by tomorrow.
你已经预定好时间了
You already booked the dates.
我就是来让你同意的
I figured you'd say yes.
你能得到什么好处？
What's in it for you?
什么好处也没有，就是为了帮助兄弟
The pure joy of knowing that I'm helping a brother.
还有，关键的来了
And, uh... Oh, here it comes.
好吧，如果我能得到好处
Well, if I was to receive a gift offering,
我当然也不会反对的
I certainly wouldn't object.
你太小心了，教士
You are caution, reverend.
我只是个侍奉上帝的仆人
I am but a servant.
好多咸肉和西红柿
Here's some salt pork and some tomatoes
你饿的时候可以吃
for when you get hungry.
谢谢你，母亲
Thank you, momma.
不要担心
Don't y'all go getting' worried now.
我会安全返回的
I'll be back directly.
我知道
I know.
向上帝祈祷，你能平安返回
Pray the lord brings you back safe.
你是特纳家的黑鬼？
You massa Turner's nigger?
我是纳特
I'm nat.
特纳在里面
Massa Turner's in here.
来吧
Come on.
- 我们到了？ - 是，先生
- We're here?  - Yes, sir.
萨姆 特纳
Sam Turner.
真准时，约瑟芬 兰道尔
Made it right on time. Joseph Randall.
这是艾伯纳
This here's abner.
这小个子是杰斯帕
This little one? Jasper.
这是牧师？是的，先生
This the preacher? Yes, sir.
纳特？
Nat?
晚上好，先生
Evening, sir.
他看着还是个小年轻？
He's a little young, ain't he?
没有，他蛮大了
Why, he's old enough.
他已经学习圣经很长一段时间了，是不是？
You've been studying the word awhile, haven't you?
学习？
Studyin'?
我能勉强训练我的黑奴们学习他们自己的名字
I can barely train my niggers to learn their own names.
来吧
Come on!
这是艰难时刻
It's hard times
对于我和你这些小农场主来说
for small farmers  like you and myself.
现在情况更糟糕了
Breakin' even's hard enough,
黑奴要想出入头地是不可能的
but getting ahead's impossible.
我只能做个好人
So to save some,
把他们带回来每天管顿饭吃
I cut them back to a meal a day per head now.
他们当中有一小部分人开始变得不安躁动
A few of them started getting' fidgety,
所以我让艾伯纳陪着我一起
so I had abner come down on 'em.
艾伯纳，这儿，他是我唯一真正的护身符
Abner, here, he's my only real protection.
现在，这些黑奴让我不满意，你要和他们说
Now, they needs to mind me. You speak on that.
他们所有的财富都在天堂里
They treasure in heaven from submittin' and all.
如果他们感到悲伤或是继续这样
If they gets to moanin' or carryin' on,
我可以毫不怜悯的分文不给
ou don't pay 'em no mind,
因为他们太懒惰了就好像生活在地狱里
because they lazy as all hell.
他们出工不出力
They do anything to get outta work.
你准备好了吗，伙计？
You ready, boy?
听着，今晚我请了牧师来
Listen up! Got a preacher here tonight.
过来，孩子
Come here, boy.
你们看他和你们一样都是黑人
Now, he's a nigger here like y'all,
他会告诉你们关于上帝的好处
and he's here to talk to you about the lord.
你们注意听着
So you listen to him
你们照样做也可以上天堂的，知道吗？
and you might just make it into heaven, you hear?
兄弟姐妹
Brothers and sisters.
我带你见彼得
I lead you to Peter 2:18.
奴隶们，奉献自己
"Slaves, submit yourselves
带着你所有的尊敬去你的主人那
"to your masters with all respect."
不仅那些好的和体贴
"Not only to those who are good and considerate,
但那些严厉的
"but also to those who are harsh."
你确定晚上不住这？
You sure you don't wanna stay the night?
拿些好的白兰地来
Got some fine Brandy
有几个女孩关在地窖里
and a couple of choice wenches in the cellar.
让艾伯纳来给我们拉小提琴
Get abner here to strike out the fiddle
让女士和我们围坐在壁炉边
and sit around the fire, tell some old lies, huh?
不了，我们要赶在太阳落山前回家
No. We best be gettin' back before sun go down.
好的，你自便吧
All right. Suit yourself.
我可以带瓶白兰地
Would take a bottle of that Brandy,
如果你愿意分给我的话
if you could spare it.
哦，小事一件，艾伯纳？
Oh, sure thing. Abner?
有了那个巧克力帮我办事
I got a chocolate one here
我可真是省力不少啊
that does it right every time.
你确定不要留下过夜了？
You sure you don't wanna stay?
不了，他们等着我们回去
No, they expectin' us back. You know how it is.
好的
All right.
你是个聪明人，萨姆
You's a smart man, Sam.
你带着那家伙前途光明
Man make a fortune with that boy.
和你做生意很愉快
Great doin' business with you.
走吧
Let's go.
你还好吗？
You all right?
S
Yeah.
那边的那件衣服
The dress there.
是你婚礼时穿过的吧？
That the one you were wearing that day?
对的
Yes.
是妈妈从她衣服里选给你的吗？
Momma offered you one of hers?
是的
She did.
阿比盖尔 海恩
"Abigail hayne."
我的母亲
My momma.
麦迪森海恩，那是谁？
"Madison hayne." Who was that?
是我
That's me.
我母亲
My momma,
她给我穿上这件裙子的时候
she put this dress on me
他们把我从她身边夺走了
the day they took me from her.
看见这块补丁
Showed me this here patch.
它提醒着我永远不要忘了我是谁
Told me to never forget who I was,
还有我的母亲
and that I had a momma.
她就在某个地方
And that she was somewhere,
我时刻都在思念着她，爱着她
missing me and loving me.
我那时十三岁
I was 13.
如果愿意我可以叫你麦迪森
I can call ya Madison, if ya like.
只要你喜欢，怎么叫都行
You can call me whatever you want.
你是我的皇后
I'll call you queen.
有什么不对吗？
What's wrong?
我们要有孩子了
We're gonna have a baby.
孩子？
A baby?
你肯定？
You sure?
你疯了？
You mad?
疯了？
Mad?
没有
No. No.
我没疯
I ain't mad.
作为仆人的眼睛
"...as the eyes of the servants
看向他们主人的双手
"look unto the hand of their masters
女仆的眼睛
"and the eyes of a maid
看向她主人的双手
"look unto the hand of her mistress..."
诺亚醒了酒
"...and Noah awoke from his wine
知道了小儿子向他所做的事
"and knew what his youngest son had done unto him.
他说到，迦南该受诅咒
"And he said,  'cursed be canaan.'"
必给他弟兄做奴仆的奴仆
"...servant of servants shall he be unto his brethren.
他说到，我们在天上的父神
"And he said, blessed be the lord,
耶和华闪的神 愿迦南
"god of shem, and canaan..."
等在这
Wait here.
我去后面看下
I'll go check 'round back.
好的
Yessum.
你在我地盘干什么？
Whatcha doin' on my land?
嗨，叫你的狗走开
Hey! Call off your dog!
你在我地盘干什么？
Whatcha doin' on my land?
不要，他和我一起的
No! He's with me!
你他妈是谁？
Who the hell are you?
我是萨缪尔特纳，沃尔索尔教士派我们来的
I'm Samuel Turner. Reverend walthall sent us.
一个伙计和一个黑鬼牧师
Fella with the nigger preacher.
来吧
Come on!
我们去找厄尔
Let's go find Earl.
你还好吗？
You all right? Come on.
在这黑鬼就是黑鬼
Niggers is niggers here.
我们不会把他们当成其它人来对待
Now, we don't treat none no different than another.
我们这有规矩
We got rules.
偷窃，财产损失
Cost of breakin' 'em, stealin', sassin',
或者其它我和厄尔能想到的事情
or any other thing that Earl and I think
任何的损失我们都会让他们遭到皮肉之苦
worth dealin' with, will be paid for in skin.
你要是干涉
You interfere with that,
我们会向你开枪
we'll shoot you where you stand.
还有问题吗？
Got any problem with that,
你也可以不干，从哪来回哪去
you can stop right now and go on back where you came from.
快点
Come on now! Come on!
厄尔
Earl!
这是萨姆 特纳
This here is Sam Turner,
还有个黑鬼牧师
fella with the nigger preacher.
你说你从哪里来的？
Where you say you come from?
南安普顿乡
We from here. Southampton county.
就在诺托韦的南面
Just south of nottoway.
嗯
Mmm.
罗塔 扬基 让他们走
Lotta Yankees makin' their way down that way.
暴民们正在对我们的人生进行破坏
Rabble-rousin', stirring shit on our way of life.
出同样问题了
They're pullin' that same shit.
厄尔，有个小麻烦
Earl. Got a little problem.
那个？这个
Which one? This one.
多久了？
How long?
大概一天左右
Mmm. About a day or so.
你不吃饭？
You ain't gonna eat, hmm?
你不吃饭，来吧
You gonna eat? Come on. You ain't gonna eat?
嗯？
Hmm? Hmm? Hmm?
好吧
All right.
这个不行，那就用另外的办法了
If it ain't one thing, it's another.
你肯定疑惑我们为什么要用你黑鬼？
You wonderin' why we could use that nigger of yours?
张开他的嘴
You're seein' it firsthand. All right, get his mouth open.
好的，美国佬
Well, if it ain't the yanks...
是干旱
...it's the drought.
如果不是干旱
If not the drought...
是这该死的叛乱
...it's goddamn mutiny.
把漏斗放这
Get a funnel in there.
即便是黑鬼们所惧怕
Truth is, even the meanest nigger's
的那些福音
fearful of the gospel.
从你的人嘴说出来也是最美好的话语
Maybe a good word from your boy there,
这些话要比我的手枪更有用
discipline word,go a lot furtherthan my pistol would.
纳特是个好牧师
Nat's a good preacher.
我才不关心他的好坏
I don't right care how good he is,
关键是他支持什么
long as he say what he's supposed to.
弟兄们
Brethren.
我向上祈祷你们的罪过
I pray you sing to the lord
你们的罪过
a new song.
歌颂义人在会中
Sing praise in assembly of the righteous.
愿圣民因所得的荣耀高兴
Let the saints be joyful in glory.
让他们大声歌唱
Let them sing aloud on their beds.
高声赞美主
Let the high praise of god
通过我们圣徒的口
be on the mouths of the saints,
他们手中握着双刃剑
and a two-edge sword in their hand
要斩断恶魔家园的复仇之火
to execute vengeance on the demonic nations,
还要惩罚那些
and punishmenton those peoples
束缚住他们国王双眼
to bind their kingswith chains
用枷锁捆绑住他们贵族的人们
and their nobleswith fetters of iron
去斩断他们，给予他们公正的审判
to execute on them this written judgment.
荣誉属于他所有的圣徒
This honor hath all his saints!
赞美主
Praise the lord!
赞美主，歌颂他吧
Praise the lord! Sing to him a new song!
赞美主
Praise the lord! Praise the lord!
不要想着穿这漂亮
Don't suppose you got a pass anywhere
裙子到处乱走
underneath that pretty dress.
没有，先生
No, sir.
我是有主人的，这儿是他的私人领地
I belongs to massa guiles and this here his property.
你骗我？
You sassin' me, girl?
没有
No, sir.
任何人都知道州法律的规定
Anybody that knows nothin' knows that state law says
法律规定如果一个黑人出现在小于树木线十步的地方
that if a nigger's less than 10 paces from a tree line,
那这个黑人需要通行证
that nigger need a pass.
好吧，先生，我可以拿到的
Well, sir, I can get one.
你无处可去
You ain't goin' nowhere.
要么你给我看通行证
Either you gonna show me a pass,
要不你给我看些其它的
or you gonna show me somethin' else.
什么？
What?
抱歉打扰了
I'm sorry to disturb ya,
但是纳特有事对你说
but nat's gotta talk to you.
发生了些可怕的事情
Somethin' awful had happened.
不管什么情况，告诉他
Whatever it is, just tell him
我早上会来这
I'll get to it in the mornin'.
主人，如果你能抽点时间
Massa, if you could just see nat
见下纳特
for just a moment, I...
见鬼了，艾塞亚
Goddamnit, Isaiah.
好了，告诉他我会在前面走廊那见他
All right, tell him I'll meet him on the front porch.
我就在这，先生
I'm right here, sir.
进来吧
Might as well come in then.
先生，我对此十分抱歉
Sir, I am awfully sorry about all this. I...
什么情况，纳特？
What is it, nat?
是切瑞，她受了很重的伤
Cherry... she's been hurt real bad.
什么伤？
Whatcha mean hurt?
几个人，先生
A group of men, sir.
艾塞亚，给我拿些纸来
Isaiah, fetch me some paper. Yeah.
好的，你下来吧
All right, you should go down there.
带上朱庇特，但不要惹麻烦
Take Jupiter, but don't start no trouble.
呆一晚上，早上回来开始做事
Stay the night, come back first thing in the morning.
好的，先生，谢谢了
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
上帝会惩罚那些人的
God's gonna punish whoever did this.
禽兽
Monsters.
纳特？
Nat?
我在这
I'm right here.
是我
It's me now.
我在这
I'm right here.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不要，不需要道歉
No, no. You don't apologize.
你不要责怪自己
You don't owe that to nobody.
告诉我是谁干的
You need to tell me who done this to you.
我会处理的，你听见吗？
'Cause I'm gonna take care of it, you hear?
我的神啊
On my soul.
我需要你的指引
I need you to tell me now.
收刀入鞘吧
"Put up again thy sword into his place.
凡动刀的
"For all they that take the sword
必死在刀下
"shall pass with the sword."
你曾经教过我
You taught me that.
我需要你
I need you here.
乔安娜也需要
Joanna, too.
把这个留给上帝
Leave this to the lord.
你要见我，先生？
You wanted to see me, sir?
是的，切瑞怎么样了？
Yeah. How's cherry?
我相信她会好起来的
I'm believin' she'll be fine.
那就好
Good. Good.
我还能做些什么
Not many woulda let you go like I did.
谢谢
Thank you, sir.
嗯
Mmm.
我们今晚有个重要的活动
We're having a big get-together tonight
有很多重要人物出席
with a lot of very important people.
自从我父亲去世后就没有这样过
Kind of like when daddy was alive.
所以我需要你，还要几个人在这帮忙
So I'm gonna need you and a couple of others in the house.
还有谁能
Anyone who's had experience
懂礼貌，服务好，有经验的
servin' and being respectable help.
明白，先生
Yes, sir.
能告诉我对您来说这些客人有多重要吗？
Can't tell ya how important this is for all of us.
如果我们做的好
If we get this right,
那么意味着特纳的姓氏会再次崛起
the Turner name will mean something again.
以赛亚
Isaiah.
是，先生
Yes, sir.
就像你知道那样，这次年度晚宴
As you all know, this annual dinner
是我们的父亲多年来的传统
was a tradition of our daddy many years ago.
在他所有的崇尚中，家庭地位，信念
And for all he believed, he placed family, faith,
传统是他最为看重的东西
and tradition at the top of his priority list.
二十年后
Twenty years later,
我们的财富正是因为有了这些相同的优先等级而得以保持
those same priorities have kept this property afloat.
那个和即期付款都是从你这个黑人牧师那来的
That and the cash down from your colored preacher.
对的
Yeah! That, too.
希望上帝可以世世代代
May god continue to bless all of us
不停的祝福我们
for many generations to come.
对的
Hear, hear.
纳特，你可以带我们一起祷告吗？
Nat, would you please lead us in prayer?
尊敬的教士，我相信你不会介意的
Reverend, I trust you wouldn't mind.
我想不会
I guess not.
天父
Heavenly father.
我们前来感谢你的言行
We come to thank you for your word and your will.
我们祈祷并且感谢你
We pray for and thank you
为了你的保护与承诺
for your protection and your promise.
我们将顺从与你
And in our obedience,
你的敌人也将是我们的敌人
you will be an enemy to our enemies.
我们将反抗你所反抗的
That you will oppose those who oppose us.
继续指引着我们，我的主啊
Continue to guide us, o lord,
我们将继续跟随着你
and we will continue to follow.
穿越磨难，勇往直前
Through fine tribulation we will push forward,
认识到只有你才能作为我们的力量和源泉
recognizing only you as our source and strength.
我们将呼唤着你神圣的名字
In your holy name we pray.
阿门
Amen.
魔幻厨房
Bon appetit.
父亲总是说
Daddy always said,
三个黑胡椒放在一杯
"three black peppercorns in a glass of port,
这是最好的餐后酒
"and you got yourself a excellent digestif."
不错，黑色总是引入入胜
Well, black is always tasty.
特别是那块肉，多汁，甜美
Especially a nice piece of black meat. Sweet. Juicy.
我不干，好吗？
I ain't doin' it, all right?
我需要你离开这
Naw, naw. I need you to get out of here!
办不到，你才刚一露面
Ain't gonna happen, man. You just come out here...
嗨，嗨，嗨
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey! Ho, ho, ho!
出什么事了？
What's goin' on, huh?
- 我不同意  - 嗯？
- I ain't doin' it.  - Huh?
- 我不同意，纳特  - 什么情况？
- I ain't doin' it, nat.  - Doin' what?
他们要先对我用私刑
He'd have to lynch me first.
私刑？我们在讨论什么东西？
Lynch ya? What are we talkin' about?
一个萨缪尔先生的客人
One of Samuel's guests...
什么？
What?
一个客人要求伊森
One of Samuel's guests requested Esther, and, uh...
去找萨缪尔先生，告诉他发生了什么
Just go and talk to Samuel. Just tell him what happened.
告诉他，他会作出正确决定的
Tell him what it was and he'll straighten this out.
但这是萨缪尔先生亲自派我来的
But Samuel sent me over here personally, nat.
我不能这么做，纳特
I can't do it, nat. I won't.
汉克兄弟
Brother hark...
你是谁？
But, what... Who are you?
汉克兄弟，你觉得
Brother hark, do you think
我想为这个过来吗？
that I wanna come over here for this?
你听见了？
You here, ain't ya?
纳特
Nat!
她在哪里？
Where is she?
萨缪尔，先生，请不要这样做
Samuel, sir. Please, you can't do this.
都还好吗？
Everything all right?
都还行
Oh, it's just fine.
我会径直走进去的
I'll be inside directly.
希望你不要孤单
I hope you won't be alone.
我保证你不会的
I assure you, i will not be.
如果你把这个搞的一团糟，我发誓
If you mess this up for me, my hand to god,
我会在第二天让你体无完肤
I will lynch every one of you come mornin!
你明白我吗？
Do you understand me?
把她带来
Fetch her.
是，先生
Yes, sir.
没关系的
It's okay.
他在那，纳特，神在哪？
Where is he, nat? Where's god now?
汉克
Hark.
对不起
Excuse me.
我在找一个叫纳特的牧师
I'm looking for a preacher named nat.
因为他的罪过
He's been banned from every church
他被这个国家的所有教堂都禁止出现了
in the county for his sins.
对于他所做的事情，他已经是很幸运的了
He's lucky that's all he got for what he done.
世间对于不道德的交易有它自己的处理方式
The world has its way with dealing with the immoral.
重要的是谁来衡量发生
Above all those who cast that immorality
在他身上与孩子的这些不道德行为
on the children as he has.
但是我们所有人都是有罪的，伊丽莎白小姐
But no one is without sin, miss Elizabeth.
这个男人需要忏悔，而且需要被指引
And this man wants to repent and be delivered.
做为上帝的牧羊人，这是我的职责
As a Shepherd of the lord, it's my duty to serve.
所以
So...
我想要为他洗礼
I'd like to baptize him.
见你的鬼
The hell you will!
杰斯罗，注意你的言辞
Jethro, you will mind your mouth.
我很抱歉，伊丽莎白小姐
With respect, miss Elizabeth,
黑人不能为白人洗礼
a nigger can't baptize no white man.
我只是认为我们应该等萨缪尔先生回来
I just think we should wait for Mr. Samuel to get back.
杰斯罗，去前院等着
Jethro, go wait in the front yard.
萨缪尔先生回来前有我们在
Mr. Samuel gets back, he'll have both of us!
我不会再说第二遍了
I won't ask you again.
你等着
Boy, you gonna get it.
你确定你要这么做吗，纳特？
Are you sure you want to do this, nat?
萨缪尔不会喜欢这样做的
Samuel may not like it.
现在有很多白人围在这附近
Nor will a lot of other folks around here.
不要考虑太多了，夫人
Don't got too much choice, missus.
这个人依然属于神
This man still belongs to god.
当你站在了上帝与它的子民之间
When you stand between the lord and his people,
这会是个危险的境地
it's a dangerous place to be.
我们全家对你一直够好的
We've been good to you. My whole family has.
你就是这样回报我的
And you go on and do something like this to me.
一个黑人为一个白人洗礼，还是在我的地盘上
A nigger baptizing a white man on my property!
你知道这让我们看上去像什么吗？
Do you know how this makes us look?
这会毁了我们所做的一切
This could ruin everything we worked for!
伙计，你最好快点解释下
Boy, you better say something and quick!
圣灵立你们作为全群的监督
"Take heed therefore unto yourselves,
你们就当为自己谨慎
"and to all the flock over which
也为全群谨慎
"the holy ghost hath made you overseers.
牧养神的教会
"To feed the church of god
就是他用自己的血所买来的
"which he has purchased with his own blood."
劝…
Ex...
劝戒仆人
"Exhort servants
要顺服自己的主人
"to be obedient to thy own masters,
凡事讨他的喜欢
"and to please them well
不可顶撞他
"in all things not answering again..."
你是被买来的不要成为人的奴仆
"You were bought with a price, do not become slaves of men."
他会亵渎对抗圣灵
"He that shall blaspheme against the holy ghost
永远不会被原谅，但是非常危险
"hath never forgiveness, but is in danger..."
要防备假先知
"Beware of false prophets
就是那个披着羊皮的
"who come dressed in sheep's clothing,
但是内心确是贪婪饥饿的狼
"but inwardly are ravening wolves!"
你个黑杂种，纳特
You black bastard! Nat!
他的秘密出卖了他
"He that stealeth a man and selleth him..."
不要盯着我
Don't you eyeball me, boy!
或是如果他被发现在他的手里，他应该坚定无疑
"...or if he be found in his hand, he shall surely
被处以死刑
"be put to death!"
拉他去公示栏
Get him to the post.
嗨，伙计
Hey, boy.
如果你活着熬过来了
If you make it out of this alive,
我要让你日子更难过
I'm gonna ride you harder than hogs on slop.
去死吧
Die.
吸取教训了吗
You learned your lesson, boy?
是的，先生，我学到了
Oh, yes, sir, I've learned.
把他放下来
Go on, get him off.
你完成布道有段时间了
You're done preachin' for a little while.
我也不喜欢你和其它组成员去到处瞎跑了
And I don't want you runnin' off with any groups,
除非我和杰斯罗在的情况下，明白吗？
unless me and Jethro are there, you understand?
是，先生
Yes, sir.
好吧，去把自己弄干净些
All right, go and get yourself cleaned up.
回田里工作吧
Be back in the field come morning.
兄弟，你还好吗？
Brother, you all right?
嗨，嗨
Hey! Hey!
我看着你的祖父去世
I watched your grandfather die
在老地方
in old land.
亲眼看着他的灵魂升天
Saw him give up the ghost with my own eyes.
他看着我
And he saw me.
他的灵魂在那天得到了升华
He harnessed the holy spirit that day.
是的
Yes, he did.
我感到很自豪
I was proud of him.
非常自豪
So proud.
我依旧感谢着神灵
I still thank god
就在他死的那天
that he died that day.
他没有活着看见这些，而我看见了
That he didn't live to see the things I seen.
看着一个坚强的人被打倒
To watch a strong man broken down
被一些可怕的事情
is a terrible thing.
嗨，奶奶
Hey, Nana.
伤口缝合的还不错
The stitches held up good.
奶奶
Nana?
你还好吗？
You all right?
最主要的
Mostly.
我需要你聚集一些你信得过的人
I need you to round up a few men you trust.
让他们与我们在柏树林那见面
Have them meet us at the big cypress
就在小屋池塘那后天晚上
at cabin pond night after next.
哈克
Hark.
他还在这，兄弟
He's still here, brother.
尽管这样
Even now.
这是西蒙
This is Simon.
萨缪尔回来一个月后买了他，在诺福克
Samuel bought him a month back in Norfolk.
我记得，欢迎，兄弟
I remember. Welcome, brother.
你认识尼尔森
And you know Nelson.
欢迎
Welcome.
这是威尔
This is will.
世界变化真快，欢迎
Word travels fast. Welcome.
嗨，这是大人们的事情，走开了
Hey! This grown folk's business! Get! Get!
慢点
Hold on.
过来这
Come on over here.
从兰德尔来的？是，先生
Come from Randall's? Yes, sir.
他还是个孩子
He's just a boy.
大卫也是
So was David.
来吧，坐下
Come on. Have a seat.
我已经追随了上帝很长时间了
I've been following the lord a long time.
布道，引用圣经
Preachin', citing scripture,
从几页篇章里分享福音
sharing the gospel from the few pages
而且我也认同里面的部分内容
and sections I've been allowed.
但是回到这个现实世界，所有这一切
But I've gone back through this word, all of it.
用一种新的方式来看待的话
With new eyes.
在我现在看来，这些诗篇
I see now, for every verse
都是他们用来作为奴役我们枷锁
they use to support our bondage,
我们的自由在这看起来是一种苛求
there's another demanding our freedom.
每一个篇章都被他们证明现在对我们的这些折磨是合理依法的
Every verse they use to justify our torture,
而这些奴隶主的行为也不会轻易被下地狱
there's another damning them to hell for those actions.
上帝告诉我，接下去我们要开拓眼界
Lord has spoken to me. Visions of what's to come.
要用善良来对抗邪恶
A rise of good against evil.
有人想做首先，他必做众人末后
The first shall be last, and the last shall be first.
兄弟们，我们是被选中的
Brothers, we've been chosen.
我们要干什么？
What are we gonna do?
做大卫和基甸
Same as David and Gideon
约书亚和参孙
and Joshua and Samson.
我们要战斗，就我们六个人？
We'll fight. The six of us?
开始是这样，但是一旦开始了
At first. But once it begins,
我们兄弟姐妹就会加入
our brothers and sisters will join.
这儿可是有很多白人的
There's a whole lot of whites.
在这个国家有多少奴隶？
How many slaves you think there are in the county?
所有的种植园里有多少？白人又有多少？
On all the plantations? How many whites?
但是他们有枪
But they got guns.
我们将夺取耶路撒冷的军火库
We'll take the armory in Jerusalem.
我们也会有枪的
We'll have guns, too.
耶路撒冷？
Jerusalem?
对的，就在北方十英里的地方
That's right. It's only 10 miles north.
我们就从特纳这里开始
We'll start right here at Turner's
打出我们自己的天下
and fight our way there.
到时我们就有几百人
By then we'll number in the hundreds,
甚至上千人
thousands even.
星星之火可以燎原
The grapevine's ablaze with talks of fightin'.
奴隶制结束了
Slaves all over havin' meetins'.
他们在等待
They waitin' on something.
等我们的召唤
They waitin' on us.
我们在富勒的地方停留
We make a stop at Fowler place?
可以
We will.
我加入
I'm with you.
我也是
Me, too.
- 我们什么时候战斗？ - 很快
- When we fight?  - Soon.
上帝会给我启示的
The lord will give us a sign.
在这之前我们要保持坚定
Until then we remain steadfast,
做好准备等待上帝的召唤
ready to strike at the moment of the lord's call.
带着我们强大的信念
With the strength of our father,
我们会最终获胜的
we'll cut the head from the serpent.
我们会全部摧毁他们
We'll destroy them all.
有什么不对吗？
Somethin' wrong?
前几天晚上有个会议
There was a meeting a few nights ago.
虽然我不知道说了些什么
And although I was not privy to what was said,
我只能靠假设
I can only assume
秘密不能让太多人知道
by the secrecy that it was not altogether productive.
现在，我不明白意思
Now,  I don't know what ideas
在你的脑海四周飘荡
is floatin' around  in your head,
但是我就在你周围，足够了解你
but I been around here  long enough to know
确信无疑的结果
that the result of certain ideas
不会让你随心所欲的
is not gonna get you what you want.
我想要的
All I want,
我想代表神为了被压迫的人们
I want for the oppressed people of god.
你愿意为他们去死？
You want death for them?
为了你妻子？
For your wife?
为了你女儿？
For your daughter?
如果这是神的旨意
If it be god's will.
神的旨意
God's will?
谁让你这么坚决
And who determined you
为了这样的事情而成为一个工具？
to be the instrument of such a thing?
他
He has.
你确定
You just make sure that he's the one doin' the orderin'.
神的仆人被称为爱的领路人
Man of god is called to lead in love.
所有都会离我们而去
Anything else will leave us all worse off.
他是爱的神，纳特
He is a god of love, nat.
不要忘记了
Don't you forget that.
我不会
I won't.
我会忘记他是愤怒的神
Nor will I forget he's a god of wrath.
妈妈
Mmm...
上帝在召唤我
The lord's calling me.
去战斗
To stand and fight.
我知道这天终会来到
I knew this day would come.
我告诉自己不要害怕
I told myself i wouldn't be scared.
我的有生之年
All my life,
都在祈祷上帝能帮助我们
I've been praying for the lord to help us
或者派个救世主来拯救我们
or to send someone who could.
我们所有人都这样
We all have.
只是没曾想盼来的确是我丈夫
Just wasn't expecting it to be my own husband.
如果是上帝召唤你去战斗
If the lord's called you to fight,
你就去
you fight.
你为我而战
You fight for me,
还有乔安娜
and Joanna.
为了我们所有人
You fight for us all.
嗯？
Hmm?
谁在那？
Who's there?
纳特？
Nat?
是的
Yes.
等着，他妈的
Wait, goddamnit!
可恶
Damn it!
母亲？
Momma?
母亲
Momma.
纳特？哦，上帝，我睡的太晚了
Nat? Oh lord, i slept too late.
没有，母亲
No, no... Momma.
你今天不用干活了
You won't have to work today.
你自由了
You free.
战役开始
The battle's begun, ma.
西蒙
Simon.
西蒙会带你去里斯那里
Simon will take you to Reese's.
我要你照顾好切瑞和乔安娜
And I need you to take care of cherry and Joanna
知道我回来，好吗？
'till I get back, you hear?
怎么了？
What's wrong?
没事
Nothing.
我为你自豪
I'm proud of you.
你做了什么？
What did you do, boy? Huh?
你杀了他们？
Huh? You killed them, boy?
是你干的吗？
Is that what you did?
你杀了他们，你等于杀了我们
ou kill them and you kill us!
你等于杀了我们所有人
You killed all of us.
我们死定了
We already dead. We already dead!
你死定了
You dead.
我们死定了
We already dead.
我们要死了
We dead now!
你们
Your
之前的主人已经不在了
earthly master is gone.
你们是自由的男人和女人
You're now free men and women,
只服务与上帝
servants of only the lord.
就像上帝之剑赦免我们的敌人一样
As the sword of the lord bears down on our enemies,
让我们的祖先和未出生的孩子高兴吧
our ancestors and unborn children rejoice.
我们死了吗？
Are we dead?
没有，我说大家都活着
No. I say we are now alive,
透过这些眼睛看到的
seeing through eyes that have been denied us
自从出生以来就在受压迫和黑暗的日子里
since being born into the darkness of bondage.
与我们站在一起
Stand with us.
让你们那些被抓获的兄弟姐妹们
Let your other captive brothers and sisters
也知道自由的滋味
also know freedom.
与我们的孩子在一起
Stand that our children
让他们世代都知道
for generations to come will know
神的伟大与奇妙
that with the supernatural power of god,
我们挺直自己的脊梁
we straightened our backs
对抗邪恶
against the works of the evil one!
与我们在一起
Stand with us.
我能自己做吗？
Can I do this myself?
孩子，他走了
The boy! He gone!
呼呼
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
趴下
Get down!
嗨，牧师
Hey, preacher!
汉克
Hark!
你在外面？
Are you out there?
告诉那个人后退
Tell the men to fall back.
什么？
What?
如果我们现在发生枪战
If we have a gun battle now,
我们就永远到不了耶路撒冷
we'll never make it to Jerusalem.
我和我的人准备好了
Me and my boys is ready!
我要复仇
I want my revenge!
这不是复仇
This ain't about revenge, hark!
你们都要被吊死，你听见了吗？
You all gonna hang! You hear me?
所有人
All of ya!
祖先
The root,
不要有分歧
not the branch.
我们必须保持专注，兄弟
We must stay focused, brother.
撤退
Will! Fall back! C'mon! C'mon, y'all. C'mon.
让我们撤退
Let's fall back, y'all!
你还好吗？
You all right?
我们所有人
It's all of us.
就这？
This it?
哈克，你觉得现在几点了？
Hark, what time you think it is?
五点三十，五点三十五
5:30, 5:35.
什么？
What?
现在我会两排下来
By now I'd be two rows down,
半袋
half a bag full.
我将前往谷仓
I'd be headed to the barn,
准备喂牲口
gettin' ready to feed the stock.
我要去烟熏室烧开水
I'd be boiling water in the smokehouse,
倒在那些主人的头上
thinkin' 'bout dumping on massa's head.
我将捆绑木桶，填补裂缝
I'd be tying the barrels, sealin' cracks.
记录着树叶与稻草
Checkin' the leaves and straw.
包装和消磨这一切
Packin' and stackin' 'em up.
避开爆竹的飞屑
Dodgin' that cracker's lash.
但不是今天
Not today.
对的，先生
No, sir.
不是今天
Not today.
去向耶路撒冷？
On to Jerusalem?
On to Jerusalem.
去向耶路撒冷？
On to Jerusalem!
好了，接下去你们应该这么办
All right, this is how this is gonna work.
把武器丢在地上
You're gonna throw the weapons to the ground,
接着趴在地上
then you're gonna lie down.
快点
Do it.
上帝是我们的明灯，是我们的救世主
The lord is our light and our salvation.
我们应该怕谁？
Of whom we shall fear?
把你们的武器丢在地上
Throw your weapons to the ground!
我们要相信上帝的强大
The lord is the strength of our lives.
我们应该要害怕谁？
Of whom shall we be afraid?
当邪恶，甚至仇敌
When the wicked, even our enemies
还有我们的敌人来到面前
and our foes came upon us
要生吞活剥了我们时，他们只会失败跌倒
to eat up our flesh, they stumbled and fell!
他妈的，黑鬼们
Goddamn, niggers.
虽然你们这些主人反对我们有安生之所
Though a host shall encamp against us,
但是我们的心将不会感到恐惧
our hearts will not fear!
准备
Ready!
虽然战争会影响我们
Though war shall rise against us,
但在这方面我们有信心
in this we will be confident!
瞄准
Aim!
叛乱者
Rebel!
来吧
Come on!
趴下
Get down!
好的
Will!
回来
Get back!
我没事
I'm all right.
切瑞
Cherry.
是纳特，亲爱的
It's nat, love.
不要停
Keep on workin'.
他们在找你
They lookin' for you.
他们伤了你？
They hurt you?
么有
No.
乔安娜怎么样？
How's Joanna?
她很好
She fine.
母亲？
Momma?
她也很好
She fine, too.
手上不要停
Keep on workin' now.
其他人怎么样了？
Any word on the other men?
他们被吊死了
They been hanged.
所有人
All of them.
他们在到处杀人
They killin' people everywhere
没有理由就因为你是黑人
for no reason at all but being black.
他们说了会一直杀下去
They say the killin' won't stop
直到抓到你
'till they get you.
这几个月来
All these months
我想过
I thought...
你是不是也死了
I thought you were dead, too.
我就在这，亲爱的
I'm here, love.
我一直都在这
I'll always be.
我太想你了
I miss you so much.
切瑞？
Cherry?
你在和谁说话？
Who you talkin' to?
我在自言自语
I's just talkin' to myself.
多希望这些事情会有所不同啊
Wishin' things was different.
嗨
Hey!
那是他
That's him right there!
杀了那个黑鬼
Kill that nigger!
我知道你很愤怒，相信我，我也是的
I know you're angry. Trust me, I am too.
这个孩子犯下了屠杀罪，我们将当众吊死他
This boy committed mass murder and will hang for all to see.
拉他起来
Get him up.
下地狱去
Go to hell!
禽兽
Animal!
吊死他
Hang him!
还有什么要对
Is there something you wanna say
这些善良人们说的吗？
to these good people?
我准备好了
I'm ready.